Santa Clara, CA 95054 cesarkylecasil@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ckcasil github.com/ccasil cesarkylecasil.pink

#### **Summary**

I am a Computer Science major practicing full stack development in Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express.js, Angular, Node.js) I have experience in working with small teams using agile software programming. My primary goal is to contribute my passion for programming towards a companies vision while expanding on my technical skills.

#### Education

# University of California, Santa Cruz

Mar 2019

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

### Coding Dojo, Silicon Valley, CA

Apr 2018

Certificate of Completion, Full Stack Developer: Python, iOS, and MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack development

• Web development bootcamp specializing in front-end fundamentals as well as three full stacks. Dedicated over 1200+ hours of coding experience, including the ability to deploy a full website from client to server to database.

### **Technical** Skills

Languages: JavaScript (ES6)/TypeScript, Swift 4, Python, C, LATEX Front-End:

HTML, CSS, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, JSON, HTTP Re-

quest/Response

Database: SQL (MySQL, SQLite), NoSQL (MongoDB), Mongoose.js,

Django ORM, Core Data, CRUD operations

Frameworks and Libraries: Angular, React, Node.js, Socket.IO, Express.js, Django, Flask Development Tools: Git, Microsoft Visual Studio, Xcode, Amazon Web Services

(EC2), NGINX, Postman, Node Package Manager (NPM)

Miscellaneous: Agile Scrum Methodology, Algorithms and Data Structures,

Linux/Unix, Software Deployment (AWS), RESTful Architecture/API, Object Oriented Programming (OOP), Model View

Controller (MVC), Microsoft Office

### Experience

Freelance Web Developer, Santa Clara, CA

Jan 2018–Present

- Building Full-Stack, modern, responsive web applications for clients while providing quick feedback and support
- Managed a small team to work with clients to create websites for various needs

# MissionU, Research Intern, San Francisco, CA

Mar 2017–May 2017

- Collaborated in a small team to present a roadshow plan to reach out to local schools and community centers for brand launch
- Drafted 4 research documents from various sources that suggest 1.3 million new job postings in 2020 with skills in data science and analytics
- Curated 4 excel spreadsheets containing 151 subject matter experts, employer partner leads, and various professors to gain input on MissionU's curriculum for the data analyst program

# Garcon LLC, Android Developer Intern, Santa Clara, CA

Sept 2016–Dec 2016

- Programmed Garcons Android application using Android Studio and Java during early stages
- Rewrote the UI layout as well as updated deprecated code

# **Projects**

# Love Changing the World, INC.

Jun 2018-Oct 2018

Public website for the non-profit organization Love Changing the World, Inc. Allows donations through PayPal in exchange for apparel with LCTW branding.

• Technologies Used: React, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Google Maps API, PayPal API, Bootstrap

Gym Log Apr 2018

Personal iOS application to aid in daily workout programs. Includes a user profile, kg/lb conversion calculator, and a log of main lifts.

• Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift, Core Data, Auto Layout

# Dojo Attendance Tracker

Mar 2018

iOS application that records the amount of time spent inside Coding Dojo as well as the time spent outside; can be expanded into an attendance tracker for Coding Dojo.

• Technologies Used: Xcode, Swift, Core Location, Map Kit, AV Foundation, Core Data, Auto Layout

# Baskin Robbins Birthday 31

Feb 2018

Web application tailored to Baskin Robbins fans. Allows the user to view all flavor descriptions to be added as a favorite.

• Technologies Used: Python, Django, SQLite3, Google Maps JavaScript API, Bcrypt, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Object Relational Mapping (ORM), Object Oriented Programming (OOP)